# Walter Eschenbach

eschenbach.walter@gmail.com | (312) 848-7151

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Young professional with one year of experience as a full-stack web developer currently working remotely for a start-up information technology firm based in San Francisco, CA. I have 5 years of professional experience in finance, most recently at Deloitte Consulting. Over the course of my career, I developed an expertise in Microsoft Excel and utilized VBA regularly to automate tasks. I started to code in my free-time, discovered an affinity for web development, and am pursuing it professionally.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Technologies/Frameworks: React JS, HTML5
- Styling: Material UI, CSS3, Bootstrap 4
- Scripts/UI: JavaScript, JQuery, Fetch
- Database: Mongo DB

- Application/Web Server: Node JS, Express, Feathers JS
- Versioning and other tools: Git, Github
- Deployment Tools: Netlify, Heroku, AWS
- Design Patterns: Container-Component

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Outspoke.io | Remote / San Francisco, CA

September 2020 - Current

Intern

- Performed triage on a backlog of new features, bugs, and updates with more than 30+ contributions
- Created three custom hooks in Feathers JS with MongoDB aggregation pipelines to curate data in a "History" collection that is consumed to display the user's activity within the platform
- Leveraged Material UI to refactor 15+ custom React components with a mobile-friendly UX and responsive design
- Conducted cross-browser testing with LambdaTest to ensure compatibility with different browsers and displays
- Utilized AWS Amplify Analytics to drop Pinpoint event listeners throughout the platform
- Collaborated with a team of developers, designers and the product team for two releases of the Outspoke.io platform

## Deloitte Consulting, LLP | Los Angeles, CA / Chicago, IL

May 2017 - August 2019

Consultant

33 Management, LLC | Chicago, IL

**April 2016 - March 2017** 

Staff Accountant

Eagle Seven | Chicago, IL

**January 2015 – April 2015** 

Risk Analyst

#### **KEY PROJECTS**

## Github Battle React JS / Github API / Netlify

Web app consumes a third-party Github API and displays information on users and popular repositories

- Split code along multiple routes using ECMAScript's dynamic import
- Cached data that was collected from the Github API to improve reload time

## Paul's Auto Repair Website

React JS / Hacker News API / Netlify

Designed, developed and published a full-stack web app for local auto repair shop

- Designed wireframe, sitemap, color palette, and responsive layout
- Debugged CORS error and resolved issues related to wrapping a vanilla JS npm package with React

Weather App Node JS / Heroku

Web app created with Node JS

- Created a form that collects a location from the user and fetches weather information from a third-party API
- Served up a JSON HTTP endpoint with Express and rendered it to the browser

#### EDUCATION / ORGANIZATIONS

## DePaul University | Chicago, IL

**Graduated Fall 2014** 

Driehaus College of Business; Bachelor of Science in Finance

Level I of the CFA Program • Meetups • DePaul Alumni Association • Phi Kappa Psi Alumni